<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dino Encyclopedia</string>
    <string name="logo">Logo</string>
    <string name="onboarding_label1">Stay Updated</string>
    <string name="onboarding_description1">Get the latest dinosaur discoveries and paleontology news from around the world</string>
    <string name="onboarding_label2">Explore &amp; Learn</string>
    <string name="onboarding_description2">Browse hundreds of dinosaur species with detailed facts, illustrations, and scientific information</string>
    <string name="onboarding_label3">Discover Locations</string>
    <string name="onboarding_description3">See where dinosaurs lived and where their fossils were discovered on an interactive map</string>
    <string name="skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
    <string name="map">Map</string>
    <string name="encyclopedia">Encyclopedia</string>
    <string name="article_thumbnail">Article thumbnail</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="dino_image">Dino Image</string>
    <string name="save_to_favourites">Save to favourites</string>
    <string name="enter_dinosaur_name">Enter dinosaur name</string>
    <string name="show_favourites">Show favourites</string>
    <string name="search_for_dinosaurs">Search for dinosaurs</string>
    <string name="dino_otd">Dino of the day</string>
    <string name="dinosaur_of_the_day">Dinosaur of the day 🦖</string>
    <string name="quick_facts">Quick Facts</string>
    <string name="period_label">PERIOD</string>
    <string name="diet_label">DIET</string>
    <string name="length_label">LENGTH</string>
    <string name="weight_label">WEIGHT</string>
    <string name="location_label">LOCATION</string>
    <string name="about_label">About</string>

    <string name="desc_hell_creek">Hell Creek Formation is one of the most iconic Late Cretaceous fossil regions, famous for preserving the very last dinosaurs before the mass extinction. The area reveals rich remains of Tyrannosaurus rex, Triceratops, Ankylosaurus, and many other species that lived during the final moments of the Mesozoic era. Its layers provide a vivid snapshot of ecosystems just before the asteroid impact.</string>
    <string name="desc_morrison">The Morrison Formation represents a Jurassic world filled with enormous sauropods and fierce predators. Home to Stegosaurus, Allosaurus, and Diplodocus, it offers exceptional insights into dry savanna-like environments that once stretched across western North America. Its fossil beds reveal complex interactions between herbivores and carnivores in one of the richest dinosaur ecosystems ever found.</string>
    <string name="desc_two_medicine">Two Medicine Formation is known for discoveries that changed our understanding of dinosaur parenting. The region became famous with the finding of Maiasaura, the “Good Mother Lizard,” whose nesting grounds and juvenile fossils suggest advanced parental care. The site also preserves a wide diversity of hadrosaurs, small carnivores, and environmental evidence of seasonal, challenging climates.</string>
    <string name="desc_judith_river">The Judith River Formation showcases a vibrant Late Cretaceous world full of ceratopsians, hadrosaurs, and early tyrannosaurs. With species such as Pachyrhinosaurus and Brachylophosaurus, the region offers important details about the evolution and diversification of horned dinosaurs. Its layered sediments reveal ancient floodplains, river channels, and complex ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="desc_niobrara_sea">The Niobrara Chalk represents a vast prehistoric sea that once covered North America. This marine environment preserved spectacular fossils of Mosasaurus, Tylosaurus, and large seabirds that soared over warm Cretaceous waters. The site provides a rare window into the ocean ecosystems that thrived alongside land-dwelling dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="desc_dinosaur_provincial_park">Dinosaur Provincial Park is one of the world’s richest hotspots of Late Cretaceous fossils. With over forty dinosaur species uncovered, its badlands landscape preserves ancient river systems where herbivores and predators thrived side by side. The site offers exceptional insights into the diversity and ecology of North America’s flourishing dinosaur communities.</string>
    <string name="desc_drumheller">The Drumheller region, including the Horseshoe Canyon Formation, is famous for its dramatic badlands and dense fossil beds. Albertosaurus, hadrosaurs, and numerous small theropods were uncovered here, revealing a complex environment shaped by shifting rivers and floodplains. Its discoveries highlight the dynamic and ever-changing ecosystems of Late Cretaceous Alberta.</string>
    <string name="desc_huincul">The Huincul Formation is a key window into the world of giant South American dinosaurs. It is the home of Argentinosaurus and Giganotosaurus, two of the most impressive dinosaurs ever discovered. The formation’s fossils illustrate the evolution of massive sauropods and large predators that roamed the warm, dry landscapes of Cretaceous Patagonia.</string>
    <string name="desc_la_amarga">La Amarga Formation is best known for the discovery of Amargasaurus, a unique sauropod with striking double-neck spines. Its fossil layers capture a time of volcanic activity and shifting climates, preserving a surprising diversity of early Cretaceous dinosaurs. The site provides valuable clues about how South American species adapted to environmental change.</string>
    <string name="desc_atacama">The Atacama Desert, now one of the driest places on Earth, once lay beneath a warm Cretaceous sea. Its sediments contain beautifully preserved marine reptiles, including plesiosaurs, along with other ocean life from a time when the region was a thriving coastal ecosystem. Fossils here reveal the ancient connection between land and sea during the age of dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="desc_araripe_basin">The Araripe Basin is one of the most remarkable fossil regions in South America, known for its beautifully preserved Cretaceous life. The area yielded Irritator and Santanaraptor, along with countless fishes, pterosaurs, and marine reptiles. Its fine-grained sediments capture delicate details, offering a rare glimpse into ancient tropical ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="desc_villa_de_leyva">Villa de Leyva is a Colombian fossil treasure rich in marine reptiles from the Cretaceous period. The region is especially famous for its large plesiosaurs and well-preserved marine fauna that once swam through the shallow seas of northern South America. The site highlights the dynamic connection between ocean currents and flourishing coastal environments.</string>
    <string name="desc_lyme_regis">Lyme Regis is the birthplace of some of the world’s most iconic marine reptile discoveries. Known for Mary Anning’s groundbreaking finds, the cliffs have produced ichthyosaurs, plesiosaurs, and early fossil evidence that shaped paleontology itself. Its coastline continues to reveal new material through natural erosion, connecting modern science with its historic origins.</string>
    <string name="desc_isle_of_wight">The Isle of Wight is often called the “Dinosaur Island” of Europe due to its abundance of Early Cretaceous fossils. Discoveries of Iguanodon, Neovenator, and other species illustrate a thriving landscape of forests, rivers, and coastal plains. The island’s geology preserves both dinosaur bones and footprints, painting a detailed picture of life in prehistoric Britain.</string>
    <string name="desc_solnhofen">The Solnhofen Limestone is famous for preserving some of the finest fossils ever found, including the iconic Archaeopteryx. Its ancient lagoon environment offered perfect conditions for exceptional preservation, capturing delicate wings, feathers, and soft tissues. The site provides an extraordinary window into the transition between dinosaurs and the first birds.</string>
    <string name="desc_transylvanian_basin">The Transylvanian Basin offers a unique view into island ecosystems of the Late Cretaceous. Here researchers discovered dwarf dinosaurs such as Magyarosaurus, shaped by evolutionary pressures of isolated environments. The site reveals how limited resources, island geography, and changing climates produced some of the most unusual dinosaur species in Europe.</string>
    <string name="desc_monte_san_giorgio">Monte San Giorgio is a UNESCO World Heritage site renowned for its extraordinary Triassic marine fossils. The region preserves nothosaurs, tanystropheids, and early marine reptiles that lived in calm, lagoon-like waters. Its layered deposits provide a detailed record of early marine life and evolutionary experimentation during the recovery following the Permian extinction.</string>
    <string name="desc_flaming_cliffs">The Flaming Cliffs in Mongolia became globally famous after the discovery of the first dinosaur eggs. The site preserves fossils of Velociraptor, Protoceratops, and numerous small animals that thrived in ancient desert conditions. Wind-sculpted red rocks and richly fossilized sediments create one of the most iconic paleontological landscapes in the world.</string>
    <string name="desc_nemegt_basin">The Nemegt Basin represents a greener and wetter counterpart to Mongolia’s more arid formations. It is the home of Tarbosaurus, bulky hadrosaurs, and the enigmatic Deinocheirus. Sediments here preserve river channels, lakes, and floodplains, revealing a diverse ecosystem where giant predators and herbivores coexisted in a humid Cretaceous environment.</string>
    <string name="desc_yixian_formation">The Yixian Formation is celebrated for its exceptionally preserved feathered dinosaurs, early birds, and small mammals. Fossils such as Microraptor and Sinosauropteryx revolutionized our understanding of the origin of feathers and flight. Volcanic ash layers and fine sediments helped capture delicate structures, creating one of the most important fossil sites in the world.</string>
    <string name="desc_sichuan_basin">The Sichuan Basin is one of China’s most productive dinosaur regions, known for impressive sauropods such as Mamenchisaurus with its extraordinarily long neck. The area preserves a rich variety of Jurassic flora and fauna, revealing an environment of lush forests and seasonal rivers. Numerous tracksites also document the movement and behavior of dinosaurs that roamed these ancient landscapes.</string>
    <string name="desc_guizhou_marine_beds">The Guizhou Marine Beds preserve an exceptional Triassic marine ecosystem filled with early ichthyosaurs, mixosaurs, and nothosaurs. The fine sediments of this region allow delicate anatomical features to be preserved with striking clarity. The fossils reveal a time when marine reptiles were diversifying rapidly, adapting to new ecological niches following the greatest mass extinction in Earth’s history.</string>
    <string name="desc_kyzylkum_desert">The Kyzylkum Desert of Central Asia has yielded remarkable fossils of early tyrannosaurs and other Late Cretaceous dinosaurs. Harsh desert conditions today contrast with the once flourishing river plains that supported a diverse fauna. Discoveries such as Timurlengia highlight important evolutionary steps in the development of advanced predatory dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="desc_kem_kem_beds">The Kem Kem Beds in Morocco are famous for producing some of Africa’s most dramatic dinosaurs, including Spinosaurus and Carcharodontosaurus. The sediments represent a vast river system crowded with giant predators and large fish. The region offers a rare glimpse into an ecosystem dominated by enormous carnivores sharing the same environment.</string>
    <string name="desc_oulad_abdoun">The Oulad Abdoun Basin is one of the world’s richest sites for Cretaceous marine life, especially mosasaurs. Its phosphate-rich deposits preserve an extraordinary variety of marine reptiles, sharks, and bony fish. The site illustrates the complexity of ocean ecosystems shortly before the mass extinction that ended the age of dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="desc_tendaguru">The Tendaguru Formation in Tanzania is one of the most significant dinosaur sites in Africa. It preserves giant sauropods such as Giraffatitan, as well as stegosaurs, theropods, and marine fossils that accumulated in coastal environments. The region provides a detailed look at Jurassic ecosystems that thrived in warm, lush floodplains along the ancient shorelines of Gondwana.</string>
    <string name="desc_bahariya">Bahariya Oasis in Egypt is known for its impressive Cretaceous dinosaurs, including Paralititan and the predatory Carcharodontosaurus. The area once formed a rich coastal environment filled with large herbivores, apex predators, and abundant plant life. Many fossils were lost during World War II, adding an air of mystery to this historically important site.</string>
    <string name="desc_great_artesian_basin">The Great Artesian Basin of Australia preserves a unique dinosaur fauna that evolved in long geographic isolation. Fossils of Australovenator, Diamantinasaurus, and other species reveal a dynamic Cretaceous landscape of rivers, wetlands, and ancient forests. The region highlights the distinct evolutionary pathways of Australia’s dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="desc_waipara_taranaki">The Waipara and Taranaki regions of New Zealand contain marine sediments rich in plesiosaurs and other oceanic reptiles. These fossils document life in Gondwana’s southern seas and include species such as Mauisaurus, one of the largest plesiosaurs. The sites help illuminate marine ecosystems of the ancient Pacific realm.</string>
    <string name="desc_mount_kirkpatrick">Mount Kirkpatrick in Antarctica is the site where Cryolophosaurus, nicknamed the “Elvis dinosaur,” was discovered. Its rocks preserve a Jurassic environment far warmer than Antarctica today, revealing forests and diverse wildlife. The discovery showed that dinosaurs thrived even in high-latitude regions with extended periods of darkness.</string>
    <string name="discovery_year">Discovery year:</string>

</resources>